<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>古诗外译赏 on Weiwei的日志</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/zh/series/%E5%8F%A4%E8%AF%97%E5%A4%96%E8%AF%91%E8%B5%8F/</link><description>Recent content in 古诗外译赏 on Weiwei的日志</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://weiwei.github.io/zh/series/%E5%8F%A4%E8%AF%97%E5%A4%96%E8%AF%91%E8%B5%8F/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>上邪</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/zh/posts/poem-translations/2024-01-06-oh-heaven/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/zh/posts/poem-translations/2024-01-06-oh-heaven/</guid><description>原文
上邪！ 我欲与君相知， 长命无绝衰。 山无陵， 江水为竭， 冬雷震震， 夏雨雪， 天地合， 乃敢与君绝。 英译
Oh, Heaven, My wish to be close to you Will never wane, though my life be long. Only when the mountain peaks have worn away, Rivers have dried up, It thunders in the winter, Snows in the summer, And Heaven and Earth collide, Would I ever dare to say goodbye. 英译的汉译
哦，天堂。 尽管我的生命会很长， 但我亲近你的愿望永远不会减弱。 只有当山峰消逝， 河水干涸， 冬天雷鸣， 夏天下雪， 天地相撞时， 我才敢说再见。 这篇翻译出现在 Brian Klingborg 的一本叫《Thief of Souls》（灵魂窃贼）的小说中，这是一本环境设置在哈尔滨的侦探小说。这位作者的专业是东亚文化。小说对于东北的描写看着也比较靠谱，但主角是一位爱引用孔夫子的警探……</description></item><item><title>松花笺——李白——塞下曲六首之三</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/zh/posts/poem-translations/2024-01-06-three-dogs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/zh/posts/poem-translations/2024-01-06-three-dogs/</guid><description>原文
骏马似风飙，鸣鞭出渭桥。 弯弓辞汉月，插羽破天骄。 阵解星芒尽，营空海雾消。 功成画麟阁，独有霍嫖姚。 英译
Horses! Horses! Swift as the three dogs&amp;#39; wind! Whips stinging the clear air like the sharp calling of birds, They ride across the camel-back bridge Over the river Wei. They bend the bows, Curving them away from the moon which shines behind them Over their own country of Han. They fasten feathers on their arrows To destroy the immense arrogance of the foe. Now the regiments are divided And scattered like the five-pointed stars, Sea mist envelops the deserted camp, The task is accomplished, And the portrait of Ho P&amp;#39;iao Yao Hangs magnificently in the Lin Pavilion.</description></item></channel></rss>