<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Weiwei on Keyboard And Me</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/authors/weiwei/</link><description>Recent content in Weiwei on Keyboard And Me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://weiwei.github.io/authors/weiwei/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Layout of Docusaurus</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/every-layout/2024-03-13-docusaurus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/every-layout/2024-03-13-docusaurus/</guid><description>Docusaurus is Meta&amp;rsquo;s open source document authoring platform. It generates clean and modern document sites written in markdown.
The Major Takeaway It uses semantic HTML tags for each major part of the screen.
This is so clean we can copy over to any website we want to create.
It is React In fact it is a React Single Page App with local routing. AND it is powerful. So powerful.
The only gripe I have is that like any React App, major version update can be a bit of PITA.</description></item><item><title>The Layout of Hacker News</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/every-layout/2024-03-10-hacknews/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/every-layout/2024-03-10-hacknews/</guid><description>Hacker News is probably one of the few top sites with a table layout. A call from the distant past.
The Front Page The front page is just a table inside &amp;lt;center&amp;gt; tag. The &amp;ldquo;More&amp;rdquo; button at the bottom leads to another page, which is loaded with a new HTTP request.
The main content is again a &amp;lt;table&amp;gt; inside &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;, with each of its row as a news entry.
Page style is controlled by a CSS file which is only 178 lines.</description></item><item><title>Western grammatical influence on vernacular Chinese in the 20th century</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2016-se-western-grammatical-influence/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2016-se-western-grammatical-influence/</guid><description>Note: This is an answer to a StackExchange question: https://chinese.stackexchange.com/questions/20763/western-grammatical-influence-on-vernacular-chinese-in-the-20th-century
Regarding to how early writers are influenced by western languages. The renowned poet and translator 余光中 has written quite a lot about it. Below are some examples he mentioned in his articles.
Deliberate plurals. Traditionally plurals are only used when absolutely necessary. In the following sentence the reader doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually care whether it&amp;rsquo;s one fly, a group of flies, or fly as a species.</description></item><item><title>Dinosaurio Anacleto</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-28-dinosaurio-anacleto/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-28-dinosaurio-anacleto/</guid><description>我是一只恐龙我名叫阿纳克来多 命运安排我活过了漫长冰河期 我的朋友都已灭绝只剩下我一个 这种情况我也没法只好去接受 我很无聊因为连一个亲戚都没有 没有一个认识的人一起出去玩 只好编造一些朋友用来自娱自乐 坐在一面镜子面前跟自己聊天
但是一天早上我决定要改变运气 寄出一份电视节目的策划文书 这个节目主要面向的是家庭观众 载歌载舞还有激烈的竞赛项目 渠道经理把我叫到了他的办公室 他挺喜欢这个节目就让我开拍 我们签了合同然后过了好几个月 我就变成了电视里的著名人物
我认识了很多 封面明星，呜呜呜 我沉浸在名气 和享乐中，呜呜呜 我买了昂贵的跑车 还有海景房 但是我不开心 但是我不开心&amp;hellip; 我不开心。
我还是想念着我的那些恐龙伙伴 还有那些想追捕我们的原始人 所以一天天气不错我住到了乡下 放弃名利希望我能找到真朋友</description></item><item><title>Mi mama me lo teje todo</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-28-mi-mama-me-lo-teje-todo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-28-mi-mama-me-lo-teje-todo/</guid><description>开始只是 一只简单袜子 用来遮蔽 我麻木的脚丫 羊毛做的 是美丽的紫色 小心翼翼 用钩针钩出来 然后妈妈 织另一只袜子 因为寒冷 啃噬另一只脚 织的更长 但也更窄 还不是紫色的 是咖啡色 从那一刻开始 再没停下来过 坐在电视机前 她织，她织，她织
我妈妈给我编织一切 我妈妈编织手艺差
她给我织了一条长围巾 把路过的人都给绊倒 还给我一顶让我头疼的编织帽 她给我织了个超大手套 现在我把它当帽子戴 因为那个疯婆子织了六根手指
我妈妈给我编织一切 我妈妈编织手艺差
她织了个底部打开的书包 我的作业本都已经见鬼去了 她做了件袖长到肘的背心 然后他们就叫我弗兰金斯坦
我妈妈，我妈妈，我妈妈 我妈妈，我妈妈，我妈妈
求你快停手妈妈 再织我就要爆炸 她看着我眼神充满了怀疑 她说这样吧儿啊 用不着跟我喊话 我给你编织是因为我爱你 我爱你，我爱你 咱俩是棒针和羊毛的关系 我爱你，我爱你 你不喜欢我就织给你妹妹
（妹妹：）不——————————————
我妈妈给我编织一切 我妈妈编织手艺差
我的妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈—— 我的妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈妈——</description></item><item><title>Journal 2022-07-05</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-05-journal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-05-journal/</guid><description>Today is the first day I went back office. The office computer is behaving weird. The LCD won&amp;rsquo;t light up during startup. I may need to get it fixed another day.
And of course, I went for the wrong direction while taking the metro home.</description></item><item><title>Journal 2022-07-04</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-04-journal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-04-journal/</guid><description>Biking has cured my back pain. I should do it more!
Bought Mi 12s today. Went for the max config. Hope it won&amp;rsquo;t disappoint me.</description></item><item><title>Journal 2022-07-02</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-02-journal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-02-journal/</guid><description>Weekend. Ate some good lunch w/ family. Long afternoon naps. 20km biking with wyh in the evening. The summer evening breeze is quite enjoyable.
Things to buy:
A folding bike. So hard to choose. A phone. Probably Mi 11 in 7/4.</description></item><item><title>Journal 2022-07-01</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-01-journal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-07-01-journal/</guid><description>So the first half of the year consists of the lockdown, the work-from-home, and the generally slacking of because of my mental status. This should not continue. From the first day of the second half of the year, I will try to do more, like writing useless journals about what I do. This shall be the first, and this is what I did today:
Introduced my son to the Chinese version of Hikaru No Go.</description></item><item><title>Remember to update playwright scripts</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-playwright-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2022-playwright-docker/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve had a repo that uses playwright for testing. The test runs daily with Jenkins and Docker. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite stable and haven&amp;rsquo;t been updated for a good year. Yesterday I tried to update playwright to the most recent version, but after updating, CI stopped working:
╔════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════╗ ║ Host system is missing a few dependencies to run browsers. ║ ║ Please install them with the following command: ║ ║ ║ ║ sudo npx playwright install-deps ║ ║ ║ ║ &amp;lt;3 Playwright Team ║ ╚════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════╝ I did feel the love from Playwright team.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Reading 2021-06-06</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2021-06-06-weekly-reading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2021-06-06-weekly-reading/</guid><description>Chinese Language If you want to read classical Chinese text printed or hand copied centuries ago:
中国古籍保护网 is a project of the National library that incorporates all the links to local libraries that have open-access scans of classical books. It&amp;rsquo;s not that open though. Some of them requires you to have an account. 汉典重光 is a project by Alibaba that aims to digitize the rare classical copies. It mainly focuses on the books that are located abroad.</description></item><item><title>Learning Rust 01</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2021-learning-rust-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2021-learning-rust-01/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;m trying to learn rust by rewriting one of my typescript libraries into rust. The purpose of the articles is that I record myself sorting things out and trying to understand stuff. They are mostly memos or notes that I serve myself. Though i&amp;rsquo;d be glad if you find it interesting, and even happier if you could point out errors and directions. Cheers.
The project I&amp;rsquo;m rewriting is silabacion. It divides Spanish words into syllables, and tries to provide as many phonetic features as possible.</description></item><item><title>Learning Rust 02</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2021-learning-rust-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2021-learning-rust-02/</guid><description>Today I found an implementation of is_vowel by BartMassey. It&amp;rsquo;s a much advanced implementation. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to analyze the code. Bear in mind that there is still much that I don&amp;rsquo;t know or understand.
External dependencies The Cargo.toml indicates that two external dependencies are used:
once_cell that provides cell-like types. unicode-normalization that does what the name says. What is a cell-like type? See std::cell. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;shareable mutable container&amp;rdquo;, and the rest is a blur.</description></item><item><title>24 Days of Hanzi</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2020-24-days-of-hanzi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/old-articles/2020-24-days-of-hanzi/</guid><description>Preface 24 Days of Hanzi for Christmas 2020, originally published in Twitter.
Day 1 #24DaysOfHanzi 咖
Have you noticed that 咖 is pronounced kā in 咖啡(kāfēi, coffee), and gā in 咖喱(gāli, curry)?
I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice until yesterday, though I already knew. Human brains are funny devices.
The word 咖喱 doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound much like the English &amp;ldquo;curry&amp;rdquo;, to the point that for long I&amp;rsquo;ve had a misconception that garlic means 咖喱.</description></item></channel></rss>