<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Weiwei on Field notes</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/authors/weiwei/</link><description>Recent content in Weiwei on Field notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://weiwei.github.io/authors/weiwei/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Journal 2022-07-05</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-07-05-journal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-07-05-journal/</guid><description>Today is the first day I went back office. The office computer is behaving weird. The LCD won&amp;rsquo;t light up during startup. I may need to get it fixed another day.
And of course, I went for the wrong direction while taking the metro home.</description></item><item><title>Journal 2022-07-04</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-07-04-journal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-07-04-journal/</guid><description>Biking has cured my back pain. I should do it more!
Bought Mi 12s today. Went for the max config. Hope it won&amp;rsquo;t disappoint me.</description></item><item><title>Journal 2022-07-02</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-07-02-journal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-07-02-journal/</guid><description>Weekend. Ate some good lunch w/ family. Long afternoon naps. 20km biking with wyh in the evening. The summer evening breeze is quite enjoyable.
Things to buy:
A folding bike. So hard to choose. A phone. Probably Mi 11 in 7/4.</description></item><item><title>Journal 2022-07-01</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-07-01-journal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-07-01-journal/</guid><description>So the first half of the year consists of the lockdown, the work-from-home, and the generally slacking of because of my mental status. This should not continue. From the first day of the second half of the year, I will try to do more, like writing useless journals about what I do. This shall be the first, and this is what I did today:
Introduced my son to the Chinese version of Hikaru No Go.</description></item><item><title>Remember to update playwright scripts</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-playwright-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2022-playwright-docker/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve had a repo that uses playwright for testing. The test runs daily with Jenkins and Docker. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite stable and haven&amp;rsquo;t been updated for a good year. Yesterday I tried to update playwright to the most recent version, but after updating, CI stopped working:
╔════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════╗ ║ Host system is missing a few dependencies to run browsers. ║ ║ Please install them with the following command: ║ ║ ║ ║ sudo npx playwright install-deps ║ ║ ║ ║ &amp;lt;3 Playwright Team ║ ╚════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════╝ I did feel the love from Playwright team.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Reading 2021-06-06</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2021-06-06-weekly-reading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2021-06-06-weekly-reading/</guid><description>Chinese Language If you want to read classical Chinese text printed or hand copied centuries ago:
中国古籍保护网 is a project of the National library that incorporates all the links to local libraries that have open-access scans of classical books. It&amp;rsquo;s not that open though. Some of them requires you to have an account. 汉典重光 is a project by Alibaba that aims to digitize the rare classical copies. It mainly focuses on the books that are located abroad.</description></item><item><title>Learning Rust 01</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2021-learning-rust-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2021-learning-rust-01/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;m trying to learn rust by rewriting one of my typescript libraries into rust. The purpose of the articles is that I record myself sorting things out and trying to understand stuff. They are mostly memos or notes that I serve myself. Though i&amp;rsquo;d be glad if you find it interesting, and even happier if you could point out errors and directions. Cheers.
The project I&amp;rsquo;m rewriting is silabacion. It divides Spanish words into syllables, and tries to provide as many phonetic features as possible.</description></item><item><title>Learning Rust 02</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2021-learning-rust-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2021-learning-rust-02/</guid><description>Today I found an implementation of is_vowel by BartMassey. It&amp;rsquo;s a much advanced implementation. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to analyze the code. Bear in mind that there is still much that I don&amp;rsquo;t know or understand.
External dependencies The Cargo.toml indicates that two external dependencies are used:
once_cell that provides cell-like types. unicode-normalization that does what the name says. What is a cell-like type? See std::cell. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;shareable mutable container&amp;rdquo;, and the rest is a blur.</description></item><item><title>24 Days of Hanzi</title><link>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2020-24-days-of-hanzi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://weiwei.github.io/posts/2020-24-days-of-hanzi/</guid><description>Preface 24 Days of Hanzi for Christmas 2020, originally published in Twitter.
Day 1 #24DaysOfHanzi 咖
Have you noticed that 咖 is pronounced kā in 咖啡(kāfēi, coffee), and gā in 咖喱(gāli, curry)?
I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice until yesterday, though I already knew. Human brains are funny devices.
The word 咖喱 doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound much like the English &amp;ldquo;curry&amp;rdquo;, to the point that for long I&amp;rsquo;ve had a misconception that garlic means 咖喱. Now that I know 咖喱 is the phonetic translation of the Tamil word &amp;ldquo;kari&amp;rdquo;, I feel much better.</description></item></channel></rss>